

ABOUT ME {...}

INTERESTS:

Photography

Playing guitar

Learning

CURRENTLY PURSUING:

Python

Dedao [Chinese audio learning platform]

LANGUAGES

- Chinese [Mandarin]
 - -Native level
- English
 - -Business level (TOEIC 840)
- Japanese
 - -Business level (JLPT N2)
- Malay Language
 - -Daily Conversation
- Chinese [Cantonese]
 - -Daily Conversation

Yap Feng Yuan

--For security purposes---Please Contact Me only through email--

<u>★: fengyuan.yap@gmail.com</u>

ABOUT ME

I am able to work well in group activities due to my outspoken and outgoing personality. I have created the best experience by becoming a Resident Assistant (RA) in the dormitory where I was able to interact with both Japanese students and International Students from all around the world. Throughout the year being an RA, I aimed to transform the language barrier between Japanese students and international students into an opportunity for them to communicate and create long-lasting friendships. During my time as RA, my unit members have bonded well and shared many happy experiences together. Furthermore, I am able to handle multiple tasks well in my daily activities. My biggest challenge as an international student in Japan was to balance my time between part-time jobs, school activities and studying. I learned how to manage my time wisely and efficiently through my living experience in Japan. My current long-term career goal is to improve my leadership skills and I would appreciate any related job opportunities that would allow me to expand my knowledge and experience.

EXPERIENCE

Mover (Part-time Job)

Yamato Home Convenience, Hachioji, Tokyo (2017-2020)

My job responsibility was to assist a full-time worker to perform a better delivery service. In addition, Yamato is a logistics company which focuses on large delivery items such as furniture and heavy home appliances. Thus, I was able to develop my attentiveness to details through handling the packagings of the items in order to ensure a safe and quality delivery to the customers.

Chef Assistant (Part-time)

Hakubun Chinese Restaurant, Shinanomachi, Tokyo (2015-2017)

My main job was to prepare ingredients to ensure the cooking process carries out smoothly in the kitchen. Sometimes, I was also assigned to prepare lunch meals for my coworkers. I learned how to work efficiently and work under the pressure during the busiest time in the restaurant.



SKILLS

Microsoft Offices [words, excel, etc]



Programming [R studio, Python]



Film Editing
[Filmora, Rush, Premiere]



Photo Retouching [Photoshop, Lightroom]

Communication Skills

Teamwork Skills

••••

Problem Solving

PROJECTS

 Wrote personal Django website hosted on pythonanywhere.com http://yapfengyuan.pythonanywhere.com

EXPERIENCE {...}

Chinese Language Tutor (Part-time Job)

World Language Center, Soka University (2016 -2017)

I assisted students in improving their Chinese language skills, focusing on areas such as pronunciation, grammar, and reading. A lesson I learned from this job was the importance to prepare and manage the session content for students with different levels of knowledge on the language. I worked my best to prepare a wide range of materials and lesson plans to ensure each student who came to my session was able to learn something new.

Vice-President of Resident Assistant

Soka University Takiyama International Dormitory (2017)

My responsibility as a Resident Assistant (RA) mainly involved taking care of dormitory students from Japan and abroad. My role was to bridge the language and cultural gaps between Japanese students and international students during their time in the dormitory. I organized activities, such as weekly conversation time and cuisine sharing to create a deeper cultural exchange among the dormitory residents. I also supported other RAs in managing the dormitory, planning for dormitory events and assigning cleaning duties. I have challenged myself in time management, problemsolving and working in groups through the experience of holding this position.

EDUCATION

Soka University, Tokyo (2016-2020)

Faculty of Economics

Result

Year	1		2		3		4	
Semester	1	2	3	4	5	6	7	8
Semester GPA	4.11	4.22	3.7	3.88	4.2	3.87	4	4.5
Overall GPA	4.11	4.16	3.98	3.96	4.01	3.99	3.99	4

^{*}The full GPA score is 5.

In School Activities Experience

- Since 2016, I participated in every preparation for the Soka
 University festival as a performance member and a member of
 the international student department of South East Asia group.
- In the summer of 2016 and 2017, I participated in a Kansai Soka Global Camp which is an English exchange program aimed to carry out English and cultural exchange with students in Kansai Soka School.
- In June of 2019, I participated in the 16th Smart Cruise
 Academy Trip to Shanghai. The trip was an inter-university
 program, and students who attended needed to give a
 presentation on a topic in groups. The presentation topics were
 related to ideas on how to improve tourism in Japan.